[bright music]
Bestfriend,
with me,
there's no need for teasing anymore.
What?
I'm not teasing you.
The heat here in the US is unbearable.
I thought it’s always freezing in America!
Yeah, that's what I thought too.
I thought that you were
topless solely for my sake.
What are you doing, bestfriend?
Isn't it obvious?
I'm cooking.
Wow!
My crush is so impressive!
So delightful!
[laughter]
So aside from working as a cashier,
you're also a part-time chef?
Let's just say, this is my way
of repaying back my roommate
for everything he’s done for me.
Repay? Repay my a♪♪!
You’re in love, idiot!
Wow, bestfriend!
It's been a long time since
I've seen you so inspired.
So when can I expect to meet the lucky one?
He's not ready for that yet, bestfriend.
But don't worry,
I'm gonna do my best to convince him.
Bring him to the Philippines.
Let's see if he meets my standards.
Sure, I'll put him in my suitcase.
Is that possible?
Won’t you get arrested at the airport?
Fine,
I'll keep him here, instead.
You amaze me, bestfriend!
But let me remind you
to take things slowly.
If that doesn't lead to a happy
ending, you might get depressed again.
And then you’ll start
doing weird things again.
And why would we not have a happy ending?
Because you’re going back to
the Philippines in a few weeks,
so you'll be embarking on
another long-distance relationship!
Then you'll find yourself
missing him constantly.
And eventually, he'll
get frustrated with you
and decide to break up
because of your clinginess.
You’ll once again blame yourself,
saying you’re not enough, whatsoever.
So where’s your happy ending now?
You're so obssesed
with long-distance affairs.
There are plenty of cute
people in the Philippines.
Why not choose someone from here?
I don't know, bestfriend.
I'd rather not dwell on it for now.
I'll just enjoy every
moment we have together.
Do as you please.
Just remember, I did warn you.
But worse comes to worst,
you'll always be there for me, right?
Here we go again.
You only remember me when...
you’re brokenhearted!
[playful music]
Hi, babe.
What did just you call me?
Nothing.
Anyways, uh,
I made lunch for you.
Yeah, how am I supposed
to eat while I’m driving?
Um,
maybe in between passengers?
When I’m in between
passengers, I’m still driving.
Okay, I just did something nice for you.
I didn't ask you to.
Yeah, well, maybe instead of
complaining, you could just say
thank you.
- Thank you for being so kind,
generous - - Fine, thank you.
Don’t call me babe.
Okay.
And you could also say thank you,
I’m just so lucky to have someone
who does small nice things for me.
I’ll pick you up at ten.
[bright music]
Oh.
Hi, how can I help you?
I'm looking for a crew
member who works here.
Oh, it's just me.
It’s my shift until closing.
How about the one before you?
- The one before me? - Yeah.
Oh, he resigned last week.
Really?
Yeap.
Where is he working now?
No idea.
He's really avoiding me.
Anyway, um, thank you for your time.
Yeah, no worries.
[street noise]
Oh, hey!
You found me!
Yeah, it’s a small apartment.
It’s not very hard.
How's your night?
Nothing new.
Did you eat the food I made you?
Yeah, it was okay.
Ah,
excuse me.
That’s adobo you’re talking about.
And?
And adobo isn’t just okay.
That’s our national food.
Everybody loves adobo!
Okay, fine.
I loved it.
It was the best thing I’ve
ever had in my entire life.
Love your sincerity.
By the way, the store manager texted me.
They have people covering
the shifts all weekend
so they’re not gonna need
us tomorrow or Sunday.
Oh, okay. So does that mean that -
Yeah, um, you’re losing two days of work
which is like 140 dollars for you.
That's... That’s not what I was gonna say.
What were you gonna say?
Well, you know, we’re
both gonna be off for a day.
Maybe we could…
go to a few places?
Well, who said I’m gonna be off?
I might end up just picking
up some shifts driving.
[bright music]
Good morning.
Who's that for?
It's just for us.
That’s nice.
But I told you I have to
go right to work today.
Yeah, I know. But you still need to eat.
Oh,
why are you still here? Go shower.
Food will be ready in a few minutes.
Where did you wanna go today?
Um,
I don’t know.
I googled several places to go to
but they’re hard to get to
when you’re commuting so...
I’ll probably just end up in the
Hollywood Walk of Fame again.
Who says you’re commuting?
Well, hello, I don’t have a car.
I know.
But I do.
Yeah, but you have work and I…
Oh.
I’m gonna go shower.
W…Wait.
What?
Mind if I join?
Do you want me to go right to work?
Nah.
No need to make any rash decisions.
I'm serious you should come back with me.
There's a lot of Koreans
in the Philippines.
If I wanna be around
Koreans, I'd go to Korea.
[bright music]
I'm gonna miss this when I
go back to the Philippines.
When's your flight?
I knew it.
You just can’t wait to get rid of me.
You're the one who just said
"I'm gonna miss this
when I'm in the Philippines"
blah blah blah.
What?
Why are you lauging?
Can you say that again?
Say what?
Blah blah blah.
Are you mocking me?
No,
I just think you're really
cute when you say it.
Shut up.
Come on, one more. Just for me.
- Blah blah blah. - Stop it.
You know what?
You should come with me
when I go back to the Philippines.
Are you crazy?
Not anymore than usual.
I’m serious. You should come back with me.
There’s... a lot of
Koreans in the Philippines.
If I wanna be around
Koreans, I’d go to Korea.
Yeah, but I wouldn’t be there.
Thank God.
[bright music]
Really?
Yeah, really.
I don’t buy it.
I think the second I leave,
you’re gonna be crying on the floor,
begging me to come back.
You wish.
I’d be relieved.
Come with me.
What would I do for work?
Don’t worry about it.
We would... figure something out.
Why wouldn’t I worry?
I’d be in a foreign country.
Yeah. But we would be together.
And that would be enough.
Wow.
That’s so dumb.
[bright music]
So are all Filipinos this romantic?
Or is it just you?
Well, we have like a
hundred romcoms every year.
There it is.
Speaking of romantic,
there was actually a customer who
came into the liquor store yesterday,
asking about the last crew who resigned.
I don’t know if they were exes.
And I didn’t really know who
exactly he was looking for but…
that was kinda romantic –
to be spending all that time
looking for someone you miss.
But maybe I have it all wrong.
Maybe the crew member who
resigned just owes the customer money.
Or
Maybe they’re part of the mafia
or some underground operation.
What do you think?
You said
he was looking for the
crew member that resigned?
Yeap,
which assumed means it's
the one who I replaced, right?
[bright music]
Can you help me with something later?
Yeah, sure.
Uh, this is a lot.
Will you help me fold these?
Sure.
Thanks.
Do you use to work in retail or something?
No. Why?
You're like really good at that.
Well, my mom used to do
other people’s laundry for a living.
And I help her sometimes.
There wasn’t really a reliable
source of water where we lived so
she would do the laundry by a river.
By hand.
I was too small to help her with
the washing and the hanging.
So I would help her fold.
How much was she earning doing that?
Oh, that was like twenty
years ago, but, um,
four, five dollars, maybe.
Oh my God.
Uh,
and how long did that take her everyday?
That took her a full day from
the washing to the folding.
And she did that everyday,
seven days a week.
Wow.
Your mom's a superhero.
Yeah, she is.
Some days, her hands would hurt, but
she would just keep going.
The problem is she would never earn enough,
no matter how hard she worked.
That's why she chose to
accept the job in the Middle East.
[soft music]
Anyways, enough about my mom.
Uh,
so what are all these clothes for?
Um, I have to return them.
Donate them.
I have to donate them.
Donate them? Like...
to a charity?
But why? These all look perfectly fine.
They don't fit anymore.
So you’re just letting go of
things that don't fit anymore?
Yeah.
[soft music]
I’m gonna get a bag. Hold on.
Group party?
Nope, just me drinking.
Oh, I do that myself sometimes,
especially when I'm
going through something.
Is that gonna be cash or card?
You should ask for my ID.
Sorry, what?
You can’t just sell liquor to people.
You should ask them for their
ID to make sure they're over 21.
Oh sorry. We don’t do
that in the Philippines.
Especially if someone
looks like they’re over 18 but
thanks for letting me know.
[soft music]
Oh hey, I know you.
You were here the other day, right?
Yeah, that's me.
Oh, did you find who you were looking for?
Yeah.
Great.
Here's your ID back.
Oh and thanks for giving the exact amount.
Uh, you know, I’ve seen
your shirt before but I'm not...
I’m not sure where.
Oh this? Um,
it’s from… donation.
Oh, that’s funny. A friend of mine…
Well, he’s not exactly just a friend.
We both like each other and…
I’d hope more comes out of it.
But anyways, a friend of mine
donated things earlier today.
I'm happy for him.
You seem like a really nice person.
What do you mean?
You said you guys are considering
taking to the next level, right?
Well,
I'm happy for him.
I’m happy for you too.
That’s really nice of you.
And don't worry, I’m sure whatever
you're going through, it’s gonna pass soon.
I don't think so.
Can I please ask you for a favor?
Yeah, sure.
[soft music]
Please give this to your friend.
And please tell him that
he shouldn't just donate
a gift he was given as an anniversary gift,
even if they're not together anymore.
I have to go.
[dramatic music]